

Portland, OR 97266 | King.NeilM@gmail.com | C: (321) 693-6115

SUMMARY

Organized and self-starting employee looking to join the IT world. I am looking to leverage my skills and experience from my 15+ years in the restaurant industry and 10+ years in film production to a technological team based environment. My years of experience have proven that I am a goal oriented, creative, and quick problem solver. While embracing my passions, I tend to seek and acquire all knowledge needed to go above and beyond in duty, no matter the task.

SKILLS

- CompTIA A+ Certified
- Mac and PC proficiency
- MS Office
- Fluent with Adobe Creative Suite and other Mac and PC applications.
- Effective team management
- Ability to prioritize and multitask effectively
- Customer service
- Self-motivated

EXPERIENCE

Head Manager / McMenamins Inc. - Portland, OR

05/2017 - Current

- Increased efficiency, effectiveness and profitability by managing team productivity, costs and budgets.
- Exceeded guest satisfaction by finding creative resolutions to problems while meeting company obligations
- Facilitated staff meetings to convey policy changes and hear employee input.
- Monitored and evaluated performance of restaurant employees and motivated to improve productivity
- Resolved issues with cash registers, card scanners, POS system, laptop and printers.
- Drove sales and add-on purchases by promoting specific item options to customers.
- Counted product stock to maintain inventory records.
- Counted drawers and local banks to validate daily records and uphold accounting accuracy.
- Conducted new hire orientations to provide company information and establish performance requirements.
- Received and reviewed candidate resume and job application submissions to approve or deny applicants for initial interviews.
- Developed effective scheduling processes to achieve production objectives.
- Utilized Sharepoint to compile data gathered from various sources.

Producer/Co-Creator / We Are Indie Horror - North Hollywood, CA

01/2015 - 05/2018

- Developed 2 websites using Wordpress and Wix programming languages.
- Directed social media and digital marketing strategy and initiatives to promote brand building, guest retention, engagement, reputation and revenue-focused activities.
- Developed and implemented strategic, social media marketing plan.
- Edited and proofread documents before being published online or sent to print.
- Leveraged media and graphic design expertise to develop engaging marketing and promotional materials, including flyers and advertisements to generate new sales revenues and grow customer base.
- Coordinated and facilitated special events, including 500 plus people parties and charity events.

Producer/Director/Editor/Content Writer / iNK Films - Hollywood, CA

05/2011 - 05/2018

- Developed and produced short films for film festivals all over the world.
- Coordinated production schedules, editing, and releases.
- Created project budgets and managed all production costs.
- Hired and oversaw employees and freelance production crews.
- Kept productions in compliance with network and legal requirements.

- Utilized and mastered Adobe Creative Suite for post-production tasks.
- Investigated technical and practical issues using knowledge base and personal experience to complete timely resolutions.

Shift Lead / Lemonade Restaurant Group LLC - North Hollywood, CA

04/2016 - 05/2017

- Created and improved daily work plans for restaurant operation, including optimizing task flows.
- Completed opening and closing duties to facilitate business operations.
- Managed and mentored 10 staff members.
- Upheld company standards and compliance requirements for operations and cleanliness of all areas.
- Allocated tasks to employees daily and monitored activity and task completion.
- Increased overall team efficiency and productivity.
- Reduced process gaps by effectively training new hires on best practices and protocols.

Front of House Coordinator / Canon Repair Center - Hollywood, CA

06/2015 - 11/2015

- Received and routed incoming calls and correspondence to promote timely communication.
- Completed supply orders and maintained appropriate levels of office supplies.
- Maintained office safety by screening visitors, updating logs and issuing temporary passes.
- Maintained master calendar for client appointments.
- Prepared packages for shipment by generating shipment invoices and setting up courier deliveries.

Server Trainer / Buffalo Wild Wings - Pasadena, CA

03/2014 - 06/2015

- Enforced staff performance and service standards to deliver consistent and positive customer experiences.
- Partnered with team members to efficiently serve food and beverages.
- Prepared and led foodservice training programs to teach staff various tasks such as stocking and restocking condiments, correctly inputting orders into the system and performing credit and debit card transactions.
- Instructed new staff members on food handling procedures and techniques.
- Coordinated optimal guest relations from initial contact through final check-out to boost satisfaction and brand loyalty.

Server Trainer/Cash Closer / Bubba Gump Shrimp Co. - Universal City, CA

05/2011 - 03/2014

- Welcomed guests with personable attitude and smile, offering to bring beverage orders while reviewing menu options.
- Maintained operations in full compliance with alcohol service standards and legal requirements to prevent incidents of overserving or underage drinking.
- Educated waiters on the menu, memorization strategies and how to convey information in a positive and upbeat manner.
- Supported management team in end of day accounting systems.
- Equipped other servers with the tools and knowledge needed to assist managers on a daily basis.
- Delivered a high level of quality service to each patron, resulting in consistent, positive feedback from guests.

Digital Imaging Specialist / Best Buy Co Inc. - Orlando, FL

10/2009 - 12/2011

- Assisted customers with resolving electronic and camera issues while maintaining company standards.
- Engaged shoppers, providing assistance and information on merchandise and product features.
- Initiated friendly conversation with each customer to determine the level of assistance required.
- Maintained assigned area to store standards by setting up and monitoring accurate ad signage and correct merchandise placement.
- Completed all assigned training to stay updated on important policies, procedures, and latest technology.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

University of Central Florida - Orlando, FL

12/2010

Bachelor of Arts: Film Studies

CompTIA A+ Certified - COMP001021694720